ICICI Laboratories' results have come out and
after the results, the stock has declined by
approximately 100 taka. The company's
operating profit has decreased by 26 taka.
We have discussed the results
with ICICI Laboratories' CFO Gopal Balachandran. Gopal Sir, welcome to
CNBC Bazaar. Sir, first of all, I would
like to know that your results for Q4 have been
a bit muted, sir, but what were the highlights on your behalf? The
industry growth in the entire Q4 has been almost single
digit, around 6%. In that
context, if you have
seen the growth of ICICI Laboratories, we have been about 8.2%. So, this is what
we had said that relative to the
industry, the growth of ICMARD will be, we will have
outperformed and at the end of the
year, I think we have been able to kind of
sustain that and so far as the
outcome is a concern, so far as premiums are a
concern and revenues.  Our concern and same
thing, if you have seen in so far as
combined ratio is concerned, when it comes to it, every
year we have been showing sign of declines
year on year in our combined ratio
which has been treasury, it has been seeing a
decline, two years ago our combined
ratio was around 105, then 104,
last year the combined ratio was
about 103.3, if you have seen the combined ratio of FI 25,
that of ICB is 102.8 8%.
So clearly, our thought process, which
I said is to drive profitable
businesses, we kept focusing on that clearly.
And since the outcome has been so far as
combined is a concern again that has been very,
very positive.  And the third thing that
we have always been telling the market is that
our return on expectation
for equity shareholders, which is broadly the
range that we had talked about, is between 16% to 18%,
if you have seen that our
return on equity for a full year
basis, that has been roughly at about 19%,
Sir, you talked about the combined ratio, that
we saw improvement in the combined ratio as compared to last year, but
despite this, we saw an impact on the profits.
Your profits have
reduced a little here.  Sir, is there a
one-off effect on the profits this quarter or is there any other
reason why we have
seen a slight decline here?   The
outcome of our capital gas will be
significantly cyclical.  One quarter may
not be necessarily
comparable to another.  And that's what we always say is that the
way we look at our numbers is
you have to always look at it more on an
annualized basis as compared to quarter
on quarter.  So that's the reason why the
profit number you see is
relatively lower in Q4 compared to on a full
year basis.  But your point on the
combined ratio again to address that the
combined ratio for quarter four of this year
on a reported basis is
102.5, the same number in quarter four of
last year was 102.3, but if you remember
what I had said in the last quarter also that the
regulator had brought a change in effective October one this year, particularly
for long term policies.
Where
he had said that the revenue recognition philosophy of the insurance company which
sells long term policies will only be allowed to be
recognized only on a yearly basis
on a year-on-year basis.  So
during that change, if you would have seen that
our combined figure of 102.5, if we compare it on a same to same
basis, then that
number will actually be at 102.1, so
actually there is an improvement even if you look at it from
quarter 4 to quarter 4
and again whether you look at Q4 or whether
you look at a full year basis, as I said,
our trajectory in terms of
improvement in combined, that is something that we are very very
confident of.
Which is especially doing combined ratio treasury, ahji
p gaya varshani sarkhamani aap yavartha jova midi rahi che
itle an important
point which you should keep in mind, but
sir I would also like to know from you that right now we are
seeing an environment of digitization.  There are
many mediators and products which are being
sold through online platforms.
Sir, if you can share some details about how you have started using AI in your business
and
how much business you are getting overall from digital channels,
if you see,
it is very useful in different segments.  So let's take health
insurance.  If you talk about health,
when a claim comes, the first point that the
customer has is to get the authorization
approval from the hospital faster.  When we
go for treatment, we
obviously expect that our approval
process from an insurance
company has to be very very fast
and there if you look again from an
ICOM stand point, there are a very large number
of procedures for which we give approval.
In fact, the time it takes to process an
authorization request is less than 90
seconds.
So Hans, we use a lot of technology there too.  A
lot of AIML is what we kind
of apply and so again if we
talk about customer experience, that is what we want to kind
of create and the
feedback is again
reflective in the net promoter scores that
customers give in terms of their
experience of our service.  If you have noticed, whether
in health or motor, our
NPS scores have been very very high.
Yes, very very well, Sir,
you explained very well how
we are seeing benefits from the digital channel.  Sir, I
would like to understand one more thing that in the
proposal that we have for bringing about many changes in the insurance sector,
one of the proposals is that a combined license will be
given in which you will be able to sell both general and life
insurance.   In that,
Sir, LIC
is also preparing to enter the general insurance business and
as we know, it is the biggest player
in insurance.  Sir, after his arrival,
you feel that there is some competition in your space,
we will
see that increasing a bit.  Have you prepared any strategy for that yet
?
On any other, any other entity entering into a
space which is kind of pretty much
existing, which is what I kind of
talked about, which
is the potential of health insurance in terms of the extent of
penetration, which is an opportunity that is quite
significant.
At an individual level, the penetration level
is a single digit number as of today.  So since the room for
players to exist is quite
significant.  What will differentiate is
claims service.  Because at the end of the day we always
say that our product
is not the insurance policy document
that we give to the customer.  Our Product
Is Claim Service.  If we look at the customer
experience at the time of claims.   Let
us make it extremely seamless and meaningful.  Then to that
extent there is no
reason why the customer should not stay hooked
on to you as a customer.  And this is
the attempt that we have been
trying to do and we have a long way to
go in terms of working on it but what we are
largely working on is to make that
service experience for more
efficient hum jo khas karni yahan thi koi
vadhare parch nahi pade but ah competition jam va se
tem sector mate sarose ek mat che sir i
would also like to know one more thing RIDAI has
asked insurance companies to bring a simple product products.  Sir, have
you done any innovation in any of your products
or are you planning to do so,
if you can tell us about it in detail
?
For us, every segment is
very varied and that is the reason why
our product bouquet has got
sessions for different set of customers whether it is
individuals or corporates or it is
a
business that we do through some of our
partnership tie ups.  So, we have got differentiated solutions for different categories
of customers
so that the requirement of every customer may not necessarily be the
same and there for again we have been at the
forefront of launching
products which we think is relevant
from a customer stand point. Yes Sir,
lastly Sir, I would like to understand one more thing
Sir, the pricing of your general insurance is
very competitive,
especially in health and motor
insurance. Sir, in such a situation,
how do you see your margin outlook for FY26?  If you
want to tell us something about it, or if you have set any target,
we do not talk about any specific segment specific
outlook generally, largely exactly
for this reason, but
largely we speak about it in the context
of the overall combined ratio treasury, which
I said that for example, in the current year,
we ended at about
112.8%. Our effort will be that we should obviously kind of improve
to further
from here, but obviously we will see that in
which direction the market is
moving, at that we can't be at a significant
variance compared to the market. If the market
shows a sign of positive change on the combined ICL
length, the combined ratio which will be
100% will be kind of moving in the direction
of a declining slope and at the end of the day the
other metrics which we keep talking about generally to the market.  Are.
If you have seen, as of today,
our return on equity
range which we have been delivering has been
between 16 to 18% as we see a further improvement
on combined performance. Our
expectation is that we are able to kind of
deliver an 18 to 20% return
on equity which is what we want to
exhibit to the shareholders.